<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-21T16:14:40+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Burak Tahtacı</title><subtitle>Arge Mühendisi</subtitle><author><name>Start Bootstrap</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hello Myself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/helloworld.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello Myself" /><published>2019-10-18T06:23:13+03:00</published><updated>2019-10-18T06:23:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/helloworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/helloworld.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Hello Myself from World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I don't the number of blogs that are established by me. And i wrote lots of time hello world posts.
    Again I am writing a new Hello World post, it's not a start of new stuff, It's end of the situation
    which I am not very lazy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    For every blog that i started, is for everybody. I was writing for express myself to others. But now
    I am writing for myself. I write, because I need. So this blog is not for you dear reader. I hope that
    I will learn lots of things, and i hope you for you too. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Hope, I will write regularly. Do not forget the 2019October18.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- SOME USEFUL CODE BLOCKS
    &lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
--&gt;</content><author><name>Start Bootstrap</name></author><summary type="html">Hello Myself from World</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Random Forest is Very Accurate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/random_forest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Random Forest is Very Accurate" /><published>2019-10-18T06:23:13+03:00</published><updated>2019-10-18T06:23:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/random_forest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/random_forest.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Decision Trees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Classification algorithms are essential part of machine learning applications. These algorithms known as classifiers.
    Lots of different classification algorithms exists in literature, the well known one is Decision Trees. Decision Trees 
    are decision support systems that simply tries to find decision rules to classify instances. Rules are computed within 
    entropy measure. If entropy of a feature is more than others than we add this feature to the tree as a decision rule.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/random_forest_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Decision Tree&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Decision trees are not very accurate classifiers. Because it's decision boundaries are strict. In real world problems, we need
    more complex (sometimes non-linear) decision boundaries. To make this non-linear we can use different classification
    algorithms such as Artificial Neural Networks (Perceptrons). Or in a short way, we can use a different approach to make our 
    classification results better. This method called &quot;ensembling&quot;. Essential idea behind the ensembling is, using different classifiers and
    combine their results. In real life we can assume that, generally a group of people can make better decisions than a single
    individual.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Random Forests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    As we can infere from name, Random Forest method includes lots of trees. For example, we have a dataset with 5000 samples and 3 classes(C1,C2,C3). In classical 
    decision tree algorthm take all the samples and generate just one tree. But in random forests, we divide the dataset into n parts and implement
    for each subset of instances and train n decision trees. In evaluation phase of model, test instance classified by all the trees in forest.
    At the and, all the results combined.

    For example results of trees is something like this.&lt;/br&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;
            Tree#0 -&gt; Predicted: C1&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#1 -&gt; Predicted: C1&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#2 -&gt; Predicted: C1&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#3 -&gt; Predicted: C2&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#4 -&gt; Predicted: C1&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#5 -&gt; Predicted: C1&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#6 -&gt; Predicted: C3&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#7 -&gt; Predicted: C2&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#8 -&gt; Predicted: C1&lt;/br&gt;
            Tree#9 -&gt; Predicted: C2&lt;/br&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;

    It's easy to say that our instance is a member of C1, because most of the trees says that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    If you are working on a classification task, using different classifiers and combining them improves your 
    accuracy. For further information about this topic you can google this terms &lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ensembling, Ensemble Learning, Bagging, Boosting, Random Forest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- SOME USEFUL CODE BLOCKS
    &lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
--&gt;</content><author><name>Start Bootstrap</name></author><summary type="html">Decision Trees</summary></entry></feed>